========================================

Privacy Policy
--------------

This Privacy Policy describes how Haystack Software LLC ("Haystack Software") collects, uses, and shares information in connection with your use of our website, services, and applications (collectively, the "Services"). This Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy") does not apply to information our customers may process when using our Services.

We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy in full to ensure you are fully informed. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or Haystack Software's data collection, use, and disclosure practices, please contact us at [privacy@arqbackup.com](mailto:privacy@arqbackup.com).

### What Information Do We Collect?

#### Information You Provide

* **Registration.** When you activate [Arq Backup](https://arqbackup.com/arqbackup/), we ask for your contact information, including items such as name and email address.  
    When you create an [Arq Cloud Backup account](https://arqbackup.com/arqcloudbackup/), we store your email address and a hash of your password so that we can authenticate you.  
    We also collect information about license activations for the purposes of advertising promotions and licensing enforcement.
* **Payment Information.** When you purchase a license for [Arq Backup](https://arqbackup.com/arqbackup/) in our [online store](https://store.arqbackup.com/), or when you enter payment information for your [Arq Cloud Backup](https://arqbackup.com/arqcloudbackup/) account, your financial account information is directed to our third-party payment processor. We do not store your financial account information on our systems.
* **Arq Cloud Backup Data.** If you use [Arq Cloud Backup](https://arqbackup.com/arqcloudbackup/) on your computer, it uploads your files to our account(s) at [Wasabi](https://wasabi.com/), encrypted with your account password or, if you chose a separate encryption password at account-creation time, they are encrypted with that separate encryption password.
* **Arq Cloud Backup Password Recovery.** If you did not choose a separate encryption password at account-creation time, the Arq Cloud Backup app on your computer uploads a separate "password recovery key set" to our cloud account, encrypted with our public key. We use this to reset your password when you request that we do so. The procedure is explained in detail in our [documentaton](https://www.arqbackup.com/docs/arqcloudbackup/English.lproj/passwordRecovery.html).
* **Communications.** If you contact us directly, we may receive additional information about you such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide. We may also receive a confirmation when you open an email from us.

#### Information We Collect When You Use Our Services

* **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.** As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. In addition, when you use our Services, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream data, landing page, and referring URL. To collect this information, a cookie may be set on your computer or device when you visit our Services. Cookies contain a small amount of information that allows our web servers to recognize you. We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, and/or clear gifs to record your preferences.

The usernames, passwords, server names and configuration settings you enter into our application for connecting to your backup destinations are **not collected or transmitted** to Haystack Software.

### What do we do with the Information we collect?

We will use contact information to email purchase receipts, software update notifications, security update notifications as well as a few helpful emails to get started with the software. We also may occasionally send out a promotional email. Nothing more than once per month and all promotional emails will have a link allowing you to opt-out of all future emails. We do not sell user data to third parties.

### Legal Basis for Processing Personal Information

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you; (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights; or (iii) where we have your consent to do so. We have a legitimate interest in developing our Services and communicating with you as necessary to provide this, for example when responding to your queries, improving our software or undertaking marketing.

### Your Choices

You may unsubscribe from receiving certain promotional emails from us. If you wish to do so, simply follow the instructions found at the end of the email, or enter your email address into our [unsubscribe page](https://store.arqbackup.com/unsubscribe). Even if you unsubscribe, we may still contact you for informational, transactional, account-related, or similar purposes.

Many browsers have an option for disabling cookies, which may prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or enable selective use of cookies. Please note that, if you choose not to accept cookies, some features and the personalization of our Services may no longer work for you. You will continue to receive advertising material but it will not be tailored to your interests.

### Disclosure

We will not disclose your email address, or other personal information, to anyone unless we reasonably believe it is necessary to comply with a subpoena, court order, law, or regulation. We may disclose your personal information to the extent required to fulfill our legal obligation.

### Security

All personal information is collected via HTTPS secure communication and is kept in a secure database that is not subject to any unauthorized usage. We employ a variety of security technologies and measures designed to protect information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information. However, please bear in mind that the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### Data Retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax, or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### Access

You may request access to information associated with your account by emailing [support@arqbackup.com](mailto:support@arqbackup.com).

### Business transfer

If Haystack Software is involved in a business acquisition, merger, sale, reorganization, or bankruptcy then your personal information may be transferred as part of the restructuring. We promise that either the acquiring institution will respect your personal information and file data in accordance with this privacy policy, or that you will be given the opportunity to opt-out of the transfer.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time, so please review it frequently. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on our websites. If we materially change the ways in which we use or share personal information previously collected from you through our Services, we will notify you through our Services, by email, or other communication.

### Product

### Support

### Company

### Connect With Us

Arq® is a registered trademark of Haystack Software LLC    Copyright © 2009-2023 Haystack Software LLC     405 Waltham St Suite 124, Lexington, MA 02421 USA
